DEVIN KENT



dalamcd@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/devinkent



615-589-2483



github.com/dalamcd

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a lover of technology and long-time hobbyist programmer of 15 years. After developing my leadership, team-building, and problem solving skills in the service industry, I decided to follow my passion for development and enroll in Nashville Software School to start on my professional journey. With a solid foundation in coding and logic, I have an intrinsic ability to pick up and adapt to new technologies and frameworks quickly, communicate clearly, and solve problems in the simplest, most efficient way.

At NSS, I have had the opportunity to work one-on-one with many of my classmates, helping them to find the simplest solution to their coding roadblocks. This type of work has helped me grow as a programmer, learning to deploy efficient code of my own as well as troubleshoot, debug and manage existing software.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Python
- React
- Diango
- CSS3 - HTML
- PHP
- SOL
- C#

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Development Bootcamp - Certificate

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Development Bootcamp

September 2020 - March 2021

An intensive six month lab focused on full-stack software development, creating applications individually and team based projects using modern industry technologies

- Developed dynamic single page applications using React and JavaScript ES6
- Learned fundamentals of HTML, CSS, JSON, REST, modular development, database management, and reusable code
- Exposure to Agile development with daily standups, planning using tickets, and group assignments
- Used GitHub for version control, using pull requests to manage projects and merge

PROJECTS

SIMULACRUM - https://github.com/dalamcd/simulacrum

Simulacrum is a single page React application where visitors can interact with and ask questions of a panel of "simulated AI" characters--famous names from history and fiction. Administrators can create new characters with associated avatar images, and use these characters to answer questions that visitors have asked in the form of a conversation between famous personalities.

FERMAT'S MARGIN - https://github.com/dalamcd/fermats-margin

Fermat's Margin is a full-stack application, a Django back end combined with a single page React front end. Users can create complex mathematical proofs by selecting from a palette of mathematical symbols including operators from set theory, calculus, propositional logic, and more. These symbols can be dragged to the canvas and rearranged, as well as be combined with text for more formal proofs.

WORK HISTORY

BLUE COAST BURRITO

2008 - 2018

Assistant Manager

- Responsible for supervising, hiring and training of all
- Created automated scheduling software for managing staff schedules

SERVICE SOURCE

2019 - 2020

Inside Sales Representative

- Managed a multi-million dollar sales territory
- Created multiple Excel macros and sheets to increase team productivity